Finding aid for the American Composers Forum Los Angeles Chapter records, 2000-2005 LSC.1974
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Administrative, 1999-2007
  - Board of Directors: Handbook: Program Overviews, 2002-2004 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors: Member Lists, 1999-2003 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Budget Reports, 2000-2003 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Bylaws, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Chapter Charter, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Chapter Director Announcement: First Year Guidelines, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Chapter Director Announcement: Lesemann, Heidi, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Chapter Handbook, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Chapter Launch: Correspondence, 2000 April (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Chapter Launch: Distribution Materials, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Chapter Launch: Planning, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Final Financial Accounts, 2005-2006 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Fundraising Fact Sheet, circa 2002 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Getty Foundation Grant, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Income Statement, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Internships: Los Angeles County Arts Commission: Charney, Joshua, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Internships: Los Angeles County Arts Commission: Foster, Mark, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Internships: Los Angeles County Arts Commission: Turi, Sarah, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Internships: Summer, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Internships: Summer, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Job Applications, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Lesemann, Heidi: Current ACF (1 of 2), 2006-2008 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Lesemann, Heidi: Current ACF (2 of 2), 2006-2008 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - LA City Grant: Extension, 2005-2006 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - LA City Grant: Original, circa 2006 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - LA City Grant: Proposal, 2007 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Letterhead, 2000s (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Los Angeles County Arts Commission: Project Planning Handbook, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Los Angeles Cultural Affairs Department Grant: Original, 2003-2004 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Membership: Awards, 2002-2004 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Membership: Awards: Leonard Stein Trophy, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Membership: Composer Bios, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Membership: Composer Audio Recordings, 2000-2005 (Box 17)
    76 CDs
  - Membership: Composer Audio Recordings, 2000-2005 (Box 18)
    73 CDs
  - Membership: Composer Audio Recordings, 2000-2005 (Box 19)
    43 CDs
  - Membership: Composer Audio and Video Recordings, 2000-2005 (Box 20)
    91 CDs and 3 DVDs
  - Membership: Forms, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Membership: General Meetings, 2000 July (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Membership: General Meetings, 2000 October (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Membership: General Meetings, 2001 February (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Membership: General Meetings, 2002 February (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Membership: General Meetings, 2002 October (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Membership: Mailing Lists (1 of 2), 2001 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Membership: Mailing Lists (2 of 2), 2001 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Membership: Mailing Lists, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Membership: Mailing Lists, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Membership: Member Files: A-F, 2000-2004 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Membership: Member Files: G-K, 2000-2004 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Membership: Member Files: L-P, 2000-2004 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Membership: Member Files: R-S, 2000-2004 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Membership: Member Files: S-Z, 2000-2004 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Membership: Sign-In Sheets, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Membership: Surveys, 2000-2002 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Monthly Reports, 2000 February-October (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Monthly Reports, 2000 April-2001 September (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Monthly Reports, 2002 January-December (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - National: Chapter Director Conference (1 of 2), 2001 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - National: Chapter Director Conference (2 of 2), 2001 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - National: Chapter Director Conference, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - National: Chapter Profiles, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - National: Monthly Reports, 2002 July-2003 May (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - National: Quarterly Bulletins, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - National: Sounding Board, 2005-2007 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Office Photographs, circa 2000s (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Office Space Planning, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Partners: Americans for the Arts, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Partners: Arts Education Groups, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Partners: Arts, Inc., 2001 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Partners: CalArts, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Partners: Cerritos Center for the Performing Arts, 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Partners: Hollywood Entertainment Museum, 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Partners: Los Angeles Master Chorale, 2001-2002 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Partners: Los Angeles Unified School District, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Press Releases, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Program Committee: Meetings: Minutes, 2000-2001 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Proposed Signage, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Sponsors: Arnold Schoenberg Center, 2001-2002 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Sponsors: Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Sponsors: Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra: Salonen, Esa-Pekka, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Sponsors: National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences (NARAS), 2001 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Sponsors: Philharmonic Society of Orange County, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Sponsors: Piano Spheres, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Sponsors: Southwest Chamber Music, 1999-2002 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Sponsors: Symphonic Jazz Orchestra, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Staff Meetings: Minutes, 2000-2002 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Steering Committee: Draft Proposal, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Steering Committee: Meetings: Minutes, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Steering Committee: Meetings: Minutes, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Strategic Plan, 2005 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Website: Launch Party: Distribution Materials, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Website: Planning: Committee, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Website: Planning: Design (1 of 2), 2000 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Website: Planning: Design (2 of 2), 2000 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Website: Planning: Web Radio, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Website: Proposal, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Workshop Committee: Meetings: Minutes, 2000 October (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Series 4: Leonard Stein papers, 1906-1988
  While not documented in the collection, Heidi Lesemann most likely met Leonard Stein through her tenure as assistant director of the Arnold Schoenberg Institute at the University of Southern California (1977-1992). As a musicologist, pianist, and teacher, Stein dedicated his life to the study and appreciation of the works of pioneering twentieth-century composer Arnold Schoenberg, first as his composition student and personal assistant (1935-1951), and later as the director of the Arnold Schoenberg Institute (1975-1991). This series contains research documents from Stein's personal work with Schoenberg, as well as his research on contemporary avant-garde music pioneer, Pierre Boulez. The files in this series range from 1906 to 1988, and include drafts of various unpublished music reviews, composition treatises, and political essays by Schoenberg, a typescript of his major work Style and Idea, as well as correspondence between Pierre Boulez and Los Angeles County Museum of Art music curator Lawrence Morton, spanning the years 1967 to 1986.
  The September 2012 addition to the collection contains administrative and promotional materials related to events held at the Arnold Schoenberg Institute from 1979-1991. Also included is the June 1980 publication of the Journal of the Arnold Schoenberg Institute.
  - Homage to Pierrot Lunaire: Copies of Sheet Music, 1987-1990 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Research Catalog: Boulez Correspondence, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Research Catalog: Schoenberg, Style and Idea, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Research Materials: Pierre Boulez, Letters to Lawrence Morton, 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Research Materials: Pierre Boulez, Letters to Lawrence Morton, 1970-1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Bibliography, Schoenberg as Artist, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Catalog of Unpublished Articles, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Composers and Conductors (1 of 2), 1923-1950 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Composers and Conductors (2 of 2), 1923-1950 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Correspondence, 1911-1948 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Criticism, after 1906 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Essays to be Translated, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Essay Transcriptions, after 1909 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Extra-Musical, before 1951 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Index of Articles, with Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Indexes of Schoenberg Archives, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Jewish Articles, circa 1938 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Miscellaneous Articles (1 of 2), 1906-1951 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Miscellaneous Articles (2 of 2), 1906-1951 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Modern Music, 1922-1949 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: On Performance, Notation, and Teaching, 1923-1931 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: On Theory, 1922-1949 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Personal Evaluations, 1923-1950 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Program Notes, 1923-1950 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Pult und Taktstock Periodical, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Style and Idea Typescript: Conclusions, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Style and Idea Typescript: Final Draft (-178), undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Style and Idea Typescript: Final Draft (179-368), undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Style and Idea Typescript: Final Draft (369-end), undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Style and Idea Typescript: Introduction, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Style and Idea Typescript: Outline, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Style and Idea Typescript: Performance and Notation, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Style and Idea Typescript: Performance Problems, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Style and Idea Typescript: References, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Style and Idea Typescript: Teaching, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold: Twelve-Tone Composition, 1925-1951 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Arnold Schoenberg Institute: Distribution Materials, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Arnold Schoenberg Institute: Events, 1979-1990 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Arnold Schoenberg Institute: Journal of the Arnold Schoenberg Institute, 1980 June (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Arnold Schoenberg Institute: Lesemann, Heidi: Correspondence, 1979, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Arnold Schoenberg Institute: Old Friends: Press Releases, Programs, Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 24, Folder 10)